Breed and Mumford Family Papers, 1698-1825/Susquehannah Company Papers, 1754-1966 Ms B4
Archivists' Toolkit
Breed and Mumford Family Papers, 1698-1825/Susquehanna Company Papers, 1754-1966
1698-1825, 1754-1966
Ms B4
Archivists' Toolkit
0.33 Linear feet (1 box, 670 items)
This collection contains letters, financial and legal papers belonging to the Breed family of Norwich, CT, merchant Thomas Mumford of Groton, CT and the Susquehanna Company.
Breed family
Mumford family
Mumford, Thomas, 1728-1799
Susquehannah Company.
Conditions Governing Access note
There are no restrictions on access to this collection.
Custodial History note
This collection was given to the library by George Pratt in 1976.
Biographical/Historical note
The Breeds lived in Norwich, CT and were in the merchandising and shipping business. Thomas Mumford lived in Groton, CT. He operated a store in New London, CT and was engaged in shipping. The Susquehannah Company was formed by a group of proprietors in Windham, CT on July 18, 1753 to claim vast tracts of land along the Susquehanna River in Pennsylvania for Connecticut.
Scope and Contents note
These papers are in one box and arranged by date. The Breed and Mumford family papers in Folders A-J consist of letters, deeds and general legal and financial papers. The places in the collection are mainly Norwich, CT, Saint Eustatius and Rio Essequibo, British Guiana. The businesses involved are shipping, storekeeping and various investment ventures. The Susquehannah Company papers in Folders K-P deal with land purchases and consist of letters and legal papers mostly to and from Norwich, CT. The asterisks indicate papers published in the Susquehannah Company Papers, Wyoming Historical and Geological Society, Wilkes-Barre, PA, 1930, VI-XI.
Other Finding Aids note
A complete listing of items in every folder can be found with the collection.
Correspondence.; Investments, American--British Guiana.; Investments, American--Netherlands Antilles.; Real property--Pennsylvania--Wyoming Valley.; Retail trade--Connecticut.; Shipping--British Guiana.; Shipping--Connecticut.; Shipping--Netherlands Antilles.
- Breed-Mumford Family Papers, 1698-1825; Folders A-J; 10 folders
  - Letters, financial and legal papers, 1698-1769; Folder A; 35 items
  - Letters, financial and legal papers, 1771-1778; Folder B; 62 items
  - Letters, financial and legal papers, 1779-1780; Folder C; 87 items
  - Letters, financial and legal papers, 1781-1785; Folder D; 111 items
  - Letters, financial and legal papers, 1786-1790; Folder E; 57 items
  - Letters, financial and legal papers, 1791-1793; Folder F; 86 items
  - Letters, financial and legal papers, 1794-1822; Folder G; 50 items
  - Miscellaneous Papers, n.d.; Folder H; 17 items
  - Transcripts of Letters, 1771-1791; Folder I; 19 items
  - Transcripts of Account and Letters, 1775-1783; Folder J; 5 items
- Susquehannah Company Papers, 1754-1966; Folders K-P; 6 folders
  - Letters, financial and legal papers, 1754-1769; Folder K; 24 items
  - Letters, financial and legal papers, 1770-1774; Folder L; 31 items
  - Letters, financial and legal papers, 1775-1776; Folder M; 24 items
  - Letters, financial and legal papers, 1782-1799; Folder N; 26 items
  - Letters, financial and legal papers, 1800-1807 and undated; Folder O; 13 items
  - Letters, financial and legal papers, 1769-1787, 1966; Folder P; 23 items